# lason D. Rodis

Software Engineer jasrodis.tk

#### **Profile**

An ambitious and dynamic software engineer with background in research and over four years of experience who works to high personal standards. Self-motivated and confident working, either on own initiative or as an integral team member.

# **Work Experience**

2016-Present	Software Engineering Fellow CERN, <u>cern.ch</u> Beams Department, Beam Instrumentation, Software Section
2015-2016	Software Engineer, CERN, <u>cern.ch</u> Beams Department, Beam Instrumentation, Software Section
2014-2015	Research Associate / Software Engineer, Scan Group, scan.di.uoa.gr Department of Informatics & Telecommunications, University of Athens.
2011-2015	Freelance web developer and administrator.
2011-2012	<b>Tech support,</b> Hellenic Telecommunications Organisation S.A, <u>ote.gr</u>

## **Education & Training**

2017-2018	Efficient Scientific Computing INFN, SCRUM training
2016	CERN Accelerator School, Communication Training
2015	FESA Hands-on Training, Introduction to MEAN.js framework, CERN, Security training
2009-2016	BSc Department of Informatics & Telecommunications, University of Athens, GPA 7.0/10.0 - 240 ECTS
2009	Graduated from "Lycée Léonin", Greek-French High school.

## **Projects & Services**

# CERN Beam Instrumentation Software Portal

Web application used for delivering and launching ExpertGuis and documenting FESA Classes Based on Maven, MySQL, Spring Boot, AngularJS, Websockets, ElasticSearch.

## **LHC Feedback Dashboard**

An expert monitoring suite for the LHC beam-based feedbacks.

Based on FESA C++, Maven, JavaFX

#### **Dataviewer**

Data visualisation library, github link.

Based on Maven, JavaFX, Jetty, WebSockets, plotly.js

Scan Group Flspace, fispace.eu, bitbucket.org/fispace

FIspace is an open-source social network platform for B2B collaboration.

Web Application - Full stack developer. Based on Maven, Spring MVC, Atmosphere Frame-

work, jQuery, AngularJS, Bower, Grunt and Keycloak.

**Diploma Thesis** based on **Univerself**, univerself-project.eu

Thesis Title: Adapting Policy-based Management of Future Networks using Collaborative Fil-

tering Techniques.

Based on Java Swing, Web services REST, owl, rdf, MySQL.

Bentley Motors EQtoolHelper

Data analysis software package of the "NAIM for Bentley" audio amplifier.

Based on Java SE, Swing, JAXB.

Freelance Various websites developed with CMS platforms, JHipster stack

# **IT Skills & Expertise**

Languages Java, C/C++, Javascript

Java EE, Spring, Swing/FX, Maven / Gradle Web html, css, AngularJS, jQuery, JHipster

Databases SQL, NoSQL, TimeSeries
Various CMS, git, Agile/Scrum, Bash
OS Linux, OS X, Windows

## Volunteering

TEDxCERN, Official CERN Guide

## Languages

Greek Native

English C2 - Excellent knowledge.

French Sorbonne 2 (C2 equivalent) Excellent knowledge.

## **Interests**

[2]

Learning, Teaching, Snowboarding, Camping, Sailing, Hiking, Travelling, Music, Trading

# **Publications & Conferences**

[3] lason Rodis, Athanasios Topaloudis, 'Common Standards for JavaFX GUI Development and its application to the Renovation of the CERN Beam Instrumentation Software Portal and Delivery Mechanism', for the 16th International Conference on Accelerator and Large Experimental Physics Control Systems, ICALEPCS 2017

Diogo Alves, lason Rodis, Stephen Jackson, 'A monitoring system for the beam-based feed-

backs in the LHC', for the Real Time Conference (RT), 2016 IEEE-NPSS.

[1] R. Arapoglou, **I. Rodis**, P. Magdalinos, N. Alonistioti, 'Adapting Policy-based Management of Future Networks using Collaborative Filtering Techniques', for the 19th IEEE International Workshop on Computer Aided Modelling and Design of Communication Links and Networks.